DAN KLEIN: So let's see
what can happen.
Well, here's this state space graph.
Let's see what tree search does.
And let's run graph search.
So at the beginning, we need
to have a heuristic.
And this is the specification
of our problem.
Here's our search tree.
We start off with on our fringe, S,
whose priority here is its backward
cost, 0, because we haven't done
anything yet on this plan, plus its
forward cost, 2.
What are we going to do?
We're going to expand it.
When we expand it, we then put its
children, A and B, on the fringe.
A's got cost 1 plus 4.
The 4 comes from the heuristic.
B's got cost 1 plus 1.
When we do that, this is
now off the fringe.
And we also need to keep
track of a closed set.
It's a set.
It's always a set.
What is on the closed set S?
We will never agree to expand S again.
We'll never be asked to, but we'll
never agree to expand it again.
According to A star, which of these
has the better priority, A or B?
B, all right.
And so what we're going to do is
we're going to expand B, and
its child is enqueued.
And that's this plan, S to B to C.
That one has cumulative cost
1 plus 2 here, right?
And then it's got forward
cost from h equals 1.
So its total cost will be 4.
This comes off the fringe.
B goes on the closed set.
We will never agree to expand B again.
Who's next?
C, all right.
What's the child of C in the tree?
Well, it's S to B to C to G, right?
So we extend the tree downward,
and now we're at G.
Its cumulative cost is 1 plus
2 plus 3, those three arcs.
So its cumulative cost is 6.
Because we're at a goal,
the heuristic says 0.
And we say we will never
expand C again.
OK, so far so good.
This is not the optimal goal, but
that's OK because it's fine when
suboptimal goals go on the queue.
It's just not OK if they come off.
OK, so hopefully A star is
going to do its job.
G is on the queue, but it's going to
sit there and rot, and we're never
going to return it.
So what happens next?
Well, we should expand A.
That's good, right?
A star search knows G got
pretty expensive.
Time to go back to A.
All right, so we expand A.
And what's its child?
S to A to C. All right, A
goes on the closed set.
Who is next in priority?
C, right?
C has priority 3.
The path to G has priority 6.
So I pick C off the fringe.
Now what happens?
It gets killed by the closed set.
I say I've already done this.
I refuse.
I will not expand it.
So now the only thing on the fringe
is the suboptimal path to G.
We return it, and we made a mistake.
We're now suboptimal.
And what went wrong here?
If we look at the heuristic, it
looks pretty good, right?
It's admissible.
I mean, the only place where you might
worry it's not admissible is
here, h equals 4.
But h is actually 4 there.
So here's admissible heuristic.
A star did the wrong thing in
the presence of the graph
search closed set check.
Why would this have been correct
if it had been tree search?
Well, we would have just taken this off
the fringe, stuck its child on,
the two goal paths would have fought,
and the right one would have won.
So the problem here is essentially,
C got used up by the
wrong part of the tree.
We got C at the wrong time.